Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, can support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

Doctoral Candidate in Information

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University M.S. in Computer Science

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Visiting Scholar Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker

National Taiwan University

B.S. in Computer Science

Ann Arbor, MI, USA 09/2015 - present

Taipei, Taiwan

09/2010 - 06/2013

Moffett Field, CA, USA

07/2012 - 09/2012

Taipei, Taiwan 09/2006 - 06/2010

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. To appear in Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction. Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%).

Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18), Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17), 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13), 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- Tsai, W.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13), 5150-5160.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17), 1700 - 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15) (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15), 1893-1898 (Presenter).

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., **Hsiao, J. C.-Y.**, Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13*), 331-336.
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao, J. C.-Y.**, Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at *The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12)*.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

Unpublished Theses and Research Articles

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2018). Social Network Matters: Opportunities for Technologies to Support Immigrants' Jobseeking. Field Prelim, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2017). Can People-Nearby Applications Benefit Newly-Arrived Immigrants? An Exploratory Study. *Pre-candidacy research paper*, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. *Master's Thesis*, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

HONOR

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

2019

Graduation Representative

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Research Assistant

09/2015 – present

Supported Dr. Dillahunt and research of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Workshop Organizer

03/2015 - 05/2015

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Collaborative Researcher

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

08/2013 - 07/2014

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

System Administrator

03/2011 - 07/2013

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES Academic Events & Activities ACM MobileHCI 2019 09/2017 - Present Student Volunteer Chair 01/2015 - 07/2015TaiCHI 2015 Organizing Committee 01/2014 - 07/2014OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) Steering Committee OpenHCI Workshop 2013 01/2013 - 07/2013Program Chair OpenHCI Workshop 2011 01/2011 - 07/2011Registration and Volunteer Chair Social Events & Activities Univ. of Michigan, School of Information 08/2018 - Present Doctoral Committee Representative Annual Taiwan Night at CHI 2015 - 2018 Organizing Committee

Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017, 2018 ACM CSCW 2017, 2018 ACM MobileHCI 2018

ACM TEI 2017

Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2017, 2018 (signed up) ACM COMPASS 2018

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

EACHING EXPERIENCE	
Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor	W. 1 2010
School of Information, Univ. of Michigan SI-622: Usability Testing	Winter 2018
Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal	
School of Information, Univ. of Michigan	Fall 2017
SI-501: Contextual Inquiry	
Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama	
Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. &	
Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci.	Spring 2013
Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design	
Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen	
Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.	Fall 2011
Introduction to Computer Science	
Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu	
Student Team Coach	
OpenHCI Workshop 2011	07/2011

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Autism Serves VolunteerTaipei, Taiwan $StarRain\ Service\ Association\ for\ Autism$ 02/2008-06/2013